weatheronline.co.uk 2018-08-16

# WeatherOnline : Privacy Weather UK weatheronline.co.uk

This Privacy explains how the WeatherOnline Ltd will process your personal information.

**Responsible party**

WeatherOnline Ltd. - Meteorological Services  
483 Green Lanes  
London N13 4BS  
United Kingdom  
E-Mail: privacy@weatheronline.co.uk  
Phone: +44 (0) 8458 694748 

**Find out about**

  * Personal information we may collect from you
  * How we use information
  * Access to your information
  * Where we store and process your personal information
  * Disclosure of your information
  * Collection and usage of location information
  * Cookies
  * How cookies can be managed
  * Data collected, processed or used by third parties
  * Security and links to other websites
  * Making changes/opt-out
  * Changes to our privacy policy
  * How to contact us

**Personal information we may collect from you**

We may collect and process the following data about you:

  * Information that you provide if you register on our online services or place an order for data or data services together with the details necessary to administer your account.
  * Information that you provide by filling in forms on our online services and subscribing to our online services.
  * Information that you provide to us when you write to us (including by email and fax) or when we speak to you by telephone.
  * Information that you provide to us by completing feedback.
  * Each time you visit any of our internet representations/websites we automatically collect and store data that your browser submits to our servers. The data submitted contains the following information: 
    * type and version of your browser
    * the operating system you are using
    * the URL of the website you visit
    * time and date of your query
The use of this data is strictly of statistical nature. We have no means to connect the data to any individual user and we also do not combine different data sources at any given time. In case we collect information regarding your IP-address this data will only be stored for the duration of your visit to our websites and deleted after your visit. 

**How we use information**  
We may use information about you in the following ways:

  * Registration details and customer information will be used to administer your account, to keep a record of which services you have subscribed to and to deliver the services you have requested.
  * To ensure that content from our online services is presented in the most effective manner.
  * To carry out our obligations and enforce our rights arising from any contracts entered into between you and us.
  * We do not disclose information about identifiable individuals to our advertisers, but we may provide them with aggregate information about visitors to our online services. For example, we may provide our advertisers with an anonymous summary of the demographics of visitors to our online services or with statistics relating to online services usage.

We do not sell or rent out personal information to any other organisations. 

**Access to your information**

You have the following rights under data protection legislation in relation to the processing of your personal data: 

The right to be informed  
The right of access  
The right to rectification  
The right to erasure  
The right to restrict processing  
The right to data portability  
The right to object  
The right to prevent automated decision making and -profiling.

Please contact us regarding any of the above issues at privacy@weatheronline.co.uk  
Please note that we may require evidence of your identity in relation to your request. 

**Where we store and process your personal information**

The WeatherOnline Ltd is responsible for the processing of your personal information. We will not transfer your personal information outside the European Economic Area (EEA) unless suitable safeguards are in place.  
Whenever we transfer your personal information out of the EEA, we ensure a similar degree of protection is afforded to it by ensuring at least one of the following safeguards is implemented:

We will only transfer your personal information to countries that have been deemed to provide an adequate level of protection for personal information by the European Commission. For further details, see European Commission: [ Adequacy of the protection of personal data in non-EU countries](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/adequacy-protection-personal-data-non-eu-countries_en)

Where we use certain data processors, we may use specific contracts approved by the European Commission which give personal information the same protection it has in Europe. For further details, see European Commission: [Model contracts for the transfer of personal data to third countries](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/model-contracts-transfer-personal-data-third-countries_en)

Where we use providers based in the United States, we may transfer information to them if they are part of the Privacy Shield, which requires them to provide similar protection to personal information shared between Europe and the United States. For further details, see European Commission: [EU-US Privacy Shield](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/eu-us-privacy-shield_en)

Our technology services providers or other contracted service providers may also have access or store data for us, but solely for use on behalf of the WeatherOnline Ltd in accordance with our instructions and under our control. 

**Disclosure of your information**

We may disclose your personal information to third parties: All personally identifiable information and/or third party personally identifiable information is subject to disclosure (i) pursuant to judicial or other government subpoenas, warrants, or orders, (ii) where otherwise required by law, or (iii) where WeatherOnline Ltd believes our property or an individual's safety or security is at risk. 

**Collection and usage of location information**

You do have the option to retrieve weather data via our apps for your specific location on your mobile devices. This requires for you to activate location services on your mobile devise. When initially starting each of those apps the app will request access to your location information. While permitting the request gives the app permanent access to your location information it can also be deactivated at any given time in the corresponding settings of your mobile device. In case you allow access to your location data from any of our apps your mobile device will transmit your location information in the radio cell that you are present at the time. In case your mobile devices does contain a GPS receiver its location information will also be transmitted to our servers. 

**Cookies**

A cookie is a small file which is placed on your computer or device after you have visited a website. You can manage cookies by changing your browser settings. This way cookies can be accepted or rejected. (see below How cookies can be managed). 

We use cookies to 

  * recognise that, as a member, you may already have given a username and password so you don't need to do this every time you visit our website
  * measure how many people are using our services, so we can improve the quality of our service and to ensure enough server capacity for speedy loading at all times
  * work with third party advertisers to serve ads on our online services. Some of these ads may contain cookies that are used to track user behavior.

### 1\. First-party cookies: WeatherOnline Cookies

a. Cookies to ensure faster loading times 

We set a cookie to mark that the user's device used to access our website/applications can display compressed data. Such cookies can help to shorten loading. The content of this specific cookie is 'GZIP=1' and it expires after 2 weeks. 

**Examples** | **Typical content** | **Expires**  
---|---|---  
GZIP | 1 | 2 weeks  
  
b. Cookies to ensure Member access to our website/application 

In case of access via our member login, WeatherOnline Ltd sets a cookie in order to recognise that you may already have given a username and password so that there is no need to do it for every web page requested. This cookie expires when your subscription ends. It does contain random letters and numbers representing an encoded time stamp and a number for internal user identification. 

**Examples** | **Typical content** | **Expires**  
---|---|---  
WOMEMBER | encrypted end of subscription | end of subscription  
WOAGRAR | encrypted end of subscription with random letters and numbers | end of subscription  
  
To manage sign-in to the WeatherOnline Ltd member service we use additional cookies. 

**Examples** | **Typical content** | **Expires**  
---|---|---  
PHPSESSID | stores user's session id | when user exits browser  
amember_nr | used in conjunction with the cookie PHPSESSID to check login status | 2 hrs  
amember_rp | encrypted password of logged in user | 2 months  
amember_ru | your username | 2 months  
  
c. Cookies to improve performance for users 

WeatherOnline Ltd sets cookies to allow selection and comparison of weather data in as few steps if possible. These cookies assist e.g. in recognising the reference date for weather data display or whether a loop or zooming of maps is requested. In cases where the user does move on to select a different region or zooms into weather maps he/she does not have to reselect the reference date: 

**Examples** | **Typical content** | **Expires**  
---|---|---  
WOSAT | ZEIT=201511170730&BIG=0&...REGION=&CONT=ukuk&LAND= | 10 minutes  
AGRARCITYTEST | Agricultural membership: encrypted user's preferred forecast locations  | when user exits browser  
AGRARCITY | Agricultural membership: encrypted user's preferred forecast locations | 17.01.2038  
  
d. Cookie to signify a user's acceptance of the cookie policy: 

**Examples** | **Typical content** | **Expires**  
---|---|---  
EULawCookie | 1 | 1 year  
  
e. Cookie set by the WeatherOnline shop: 

This cookie contains the following information: The date and time the cookie was created (in YYYY-MM-DD HH:MM:SS format), The ID of the selected language, The ID of the selected currency. The ID of the last visited category of product listings, Whether the cart block is "expanded" or "collapsed", The IDs of recently viewed products as a comma-separated list. The ID of the current wishlist displayed in the wishlist block, Whether the "Terms of service" checkbox has been ticked (1 if it has and 0 if it hasn't) The guest ID of the visitor when not logged in, The connection ID of the visitor's current session, The customer ID of the visitor when logged in, The last name of the customer. The first name of the customer, Whether the customer is logged in, The MD5 hash of the _COOKIE_KEY_ in config/settings.inc.php and the password the customer used to log in. The email address that the customer used to log in, The ID of the current cart displayed in the cart block, The Blowfish checksum used to determine whether the cookie has been modified by a third party. The customer will be logged out and the cookie deleted if the checksum doesn't match. 

**Examples** | **Typical content** | **Expires**  
---|---|---  
shop.weatheronline.co.uk | PrestShop_: encrypted user data | 20 days  
shop.weatheronline.co.uk | cookie-ue: 1 | 1 year  
  
### 2\. Cookies set by using Google Analytics and DoubleClick

WeatherOnline Ltd uses Google Analytics and Google DoubleClick For Publishers. By using Google Analytics and DoubleClick.net code on our websites and Apps, we set several cookies (see tables below) which are writen and controled by Google.

Please note, that Google Analytics and DoubleClick.net also provide third-party cookies (see below).  
a. Google Analytics 

WeatherOnline Ltd uses Google Analytics to produce anonymised statistics on how our sites are used.

**Examples** | **Typical content** | **Expires**  
---|---|---  
_ga, _gat, _gat_allsites, _gat_expert, _gat_agrar, _gat_sail, _gat_weather, _gat_radar |  identifier used to distinguish users | 2 years  
  
This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc.. Google Analytics uses cookies. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States.  
Please note that on this website, Google Analytics code is supplemented by anonymizeIp to ensure an anonymized collection of IP addresses (so called IP-masking). Thus Google will truncate/anonymize the last octet of the IP address for Member States of the European Union as well as for other parties to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases, the full IP address is sent to and shortened by Google servers in the USA.

How you can opt-out from Google Analytics:

1\. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser (see below How cookies can be managed).

2\. Furthermore you can prevent Google's collection and use of data (cookies and IP address) by downloading and installing the browser plug-in available under [tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en-GB](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en-GB). 

Further information concerning the terms and conditions of use and data privacy can be found at [http://www.google.com/analytics/terms/gb.html](https://www.google.com/analytics/terms/gb.html) and at <https://www.google.de/intl/en_uk/policies/>. 

b. Google DoubleClick For Publishers 

### 3\. Behavioural Advertising Cookies/Third Party Cookies

WeatherOnline Ltd works with third party advertisers to serve ads on our site. Some of these ads contain cookies that are used to track user behavior. WeatherOnline Ltd does not have control or access to the information contained in these cookies. You can find further information on the data collected, processed or used by third parties here at "Data collected, processed or used by third parties". 

**How cookies can be managed**

You are not obliged to accept cookies and may modify your browser so that it will not accept cookies. The browser you use to surf the web not only allows you to see the cookies that were set but also allows you to control their use.

You can control the cookies by allowing them, deleting them individually or deleting all of them. You can also set your browser to not to accept cookies altogether. If this option is selected, you should be aware that many websites will not function properly or not at all. It may be possible to set your browser not to accept cookies and ask for your consent before each cookie is set on your device. This gives you control over what is set on your device. 

There are different levels of control too. You are able to prevent just third party cookies being deployed, effectively opting out of behavioural advertising, and some even allow you to block specific companies you do not wish to deploy a cookie, instead of selecting all companies.

In order to manage your cookies, please refer to your browser Help tools. Alternatively, you may wish to visit [AboutCookies.org](http://aboutcookies.org/) which contains comprehensive information on how to manage cookies on a wide variety of browsers. You will also find details on how to delete cookies from your device as well as more general information about cookies.

A website written and funded by the internet advertising industry ([youronlinechoices](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)) provides an way to opt out of behavioural advertising from each (or all) of the networks represented by the IAB: [Your ad choices](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/your-ad-choices) and gives more information about [online behavioural advertising](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/about-behavioural-advertising). 

**Data collected, processed or used by third parties**

a. Advertising

WeatherOnline Ltd works with third party advertisers to serve ads on our site. Personal data such as IP-address and cookies are collected or used within the scope of advertisement deliveries. Throughout those advertising deliveries our advertising partners do implement cookies or similar technologies on your browser in order to follow which ads you have looked or clicked at or which subpages you have visited. 

We work with DoubleClick for Publisher, GoogleAdsense and Criteo.

WeatherOnline Ltd does not have control or access to the information collected by third party advertisers.

For more information about how third party advertisers use the collected information and how to opt-out, please review third party advertisers **privacy policy (see links below)** or our section 'How cookies can bemanaged?'

b. Sharing content with other website (Google+, Facebook,..) 

WeatherOnline Ltd only links to Social Media (e.g. Facebook, Google+ or Twitter), but does not actively embed social plugins such as Facebook's "Like" button. Only when the link is clicked, data transmission to a social network can take place. 

c. Embedded media and other external sources of cookies 

YouTube.com

**Security and links to other websites**

We use encryption software and other security measures to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of sensitive information under our control. However, the WeatherOnline's site includes links to other sites, and when you choose to visit those sites we are not responsible for their privacy policies or how they treat user information. In addition, we may permit third parties to offer registration-based services through our site. We are not responsible for the actions and policies of these third parties, and you should review the privacy policies of these parties when supplying personally identifiable information to them. 

**Making changes/opt-out**

To make changes to your preferences, update your personally identifiable information, unsubscribe to any e-mail subscriptions or to opt-out of any services, please contact us directly at privacy@weatheronline.co.uk.

**Changes to our privacy policy**

This privacy policy may occasionally be updated or amended therefore we advise you to revisit this page regularly. 

**How to contact us**

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of WO online services, or your dealings with WO online services, you can contact us at privacy@weatheronline.co.uk
